https://www.haystongolf.com/privacy-policy/

Members (All Categories),Visitorsand Volunteers
What we needHayston Golf Club will be a “controller” of the personal information that you provide to us in any Application/Entry Form and through this website.
Members/Visitors/VolunteersPersonal Data
When you register as a member of Hayston Golf Club, renew your membership (including if you are registering or renewing on behalf of a child under the age of18) or register to compete in a Hayston Golf Club Eventor volunteer we may ask you for the following personal information:
•Contact Details -Name, Address, eMail Address, Date of Birth, Contact number, etc.:
•Social Media Account Details -Facebook, Twitter, etc.:
•Membership Criteria -Full, 5-Day, Youth, Junior, Visitor, etc.:
•Payment Details -Bank Account Number, Sort Code, Card Details, etc.:
•Participation Details -for example, Player, etc.:
•Equality Information -for example, disability, etc.:
•Medical Information -for example, allergies, dietary requirements, etc.: and
•Any Other Personal Information -for example, PVG Membership, Clothing sizes, etc.
Why we need your personal information -contractual purposes
We need to collect our Members personal information so that we can manage your membership. We will use our members’ personal information to:
•Provide you with core Member Services including insurance, registration, etc.:
•Set up your online Membership Account(s)and administer your account online;and
•Send you Membership Communications [by post, emailor social media] in relation to essential membership services If you do not provide us with all of the personal information that we need to collect then this may affect our ability to offer the above membership services and benefits.
Why we need your personal information -legitimate purposes
We also process our Members’ and Visitors’ personal information in pursuit of our legitimate interests to:
•Promote and encourage participation in golf by sending members’/visitors’communications and booking information for upcoming competitions and events. Our competitions and events may be filmed or photographed and your personal information may also be used in images captured from our competitions and events, which we use for promotional, education and developmentpurposes;
•Provide competition in golf by accepting and managing entries for our competitions and checking your personal information to ensure you are entered into the correct category;
•Monitor and develop participation in golf by monitoring members’/Visitors’engagement and participation and inviting our members/visitorsto participate in surveys for researching and development purposes;
•Invite our members/visitorsas award winners or guests to our annual awards [dinner / ceremony], which includes asking our members to nominate individuals for awards and shortlisting such individuals to select the winners, who we will then contact;
•Develop and maintain our members’ qualifications, including sending email communications to members to inform you of upcoming courses, renewal requirements and verify that you have completed any mandatory training and PVG / safeguarding requirements;
•Respond to and communicate with members/visitorsregarding your questions, comments, support needs or complaints, concerns or allegations in relation to golf;
•Investigate complaints, suspend membership and take disciplinary action where appropriate
•When you book a place with us for and attend a coaching course, competition,event, etc., we need to collect your personal information so that we can honour your booking and to enable you to participate in the course, competition, event, etc; and
Where we process your personal information in pursuit of our legitimate interests, you have the right to object to us using your personal information for the above purposes.
If you wish to object to any of the above processing, please contact us. If we agree and comply with your objection, this may affect our ability to undertake the tasks above for the benefit of you as a Member/Visitor.
In respect of Volunteers’personal data, we will need to collect personal information relating to criminal convictions oralleged commission of criminal offences where you are required to complete a PVG check under the Protection of Vulnerable Groups (Scotland) Act 2007. This information will include your PVG certificate number, PVG membership number, date of issue and any relevant information in relation to your membership of the PVG Scheme.
If your PVG certificate is not clear, we will have a legitimate interest to collect references and any other applicable information to allow us to consider whether or not you can volunteer in a regulated role with children and/or protected adults.
Where we process your personal information in pursuit of our legitimate interests, you have the right to object to us using your personal information for the above purposes. If you wish to object to any of the above processing, please contact us. If we comply with your objection, this may affect our ability to undertake the tasks above for the benefit of you as a volunteer.
Why we need your personal information -legal obligations
We are under alegal obligation to process certain personal information relating to our Members, Volunteers, etc. for the purposes of complying with our obligations under:
•The Protection of Vulnerable Groups (Scotland) Act 2007 to check that our coaches and volunteers are able to undertake regulated work with children and protected adults;
•The Equality Act 2010, which requires us to process personal information to make reasonable adjustments where necessary;
Other uses of your personal information
We may ask you if we can process your personal information for additional purposes. Where we do so, we will provide you with an additional privacy notice with information on how we will use your information for these additional purposes.
Who we share your personal information with
If your personal information is included in any images or videos taken by us at our competitions and events, we may share this for promotional and/or journalistic purposes. We may be required to share personal information with statutory or regulatory authorities and organisations to comply with statutory obligations. Such organisations include the Health & Safety Executive, Disclosure Scotland, Children 1st, Scottish Golf, Professional Golfers Association (PGA) and Police Scotland for the purposes of safeguarding children and/or protected adults. We may also share personal information with our professional and legal advisors for the purposes of taking advice
Hayston Golf Club employs third party suppliers to provide services, including [Club 2000,BRS Golf Online Booking]. These suppliers may process personal information on our behalf as “processors” and are subject to written contractual conditions to only process that personal information under our instructions and protect it. In the event that we do share personal information with external third parties, we will only share such personal information strictly required for the specific purposes and take reasonable steps to ensure that recipients shall only process the disclosed personal informationin accordance with those purposes.
Players’personal data
As an affiliated club of Scottish Golf we are required to ensure that all of our Members are Members of the Scottish Golf Ltdas a condition of affiliation. We will share your name and membership category with Scottish Golf who will become a controller of your personal information upon receipt. We publish the results of our competitions on our website. These may include competitors’ name, age category, home club or country, county/area, result. We may also be required to share personal information relating to players’ health in order to undertake activities to eliminate doping, at a sporting event, within our sport generally, or to provide information about doping, or suspected doping, to UK Anti-Doping or another body with responsibility for eliminating doping in our sport.
How we protect your personal information
Your personal information is stored on our physical/electronic filing systems and our servers based in the UK/EU and areaccessed by our staff / volunteers for the purposes set out above
How long we keep your personal information
We will only keep your personal information for as long as necessary to provide you with membership services. Unless you ask us not to, we will review and possibly delete your personal information where you have not renewed your membership with us or visited in thepast sixyears.Your rights You can exercise any of the following rights by writing to usat “F.A.O. Club Secretary, Hayston Golf Club, Campsie Road, Kirkintilloch, Glasgow, G66 1RN” or by email to gm@haystongolf.co.uk
Your rights in relation to your personal information are:
•You have a right to request access to the personal information that we hold about you by making a “subject access request”;
•If you believe that any of your personal information is inaccurate or incomplete, you have a right to request that we correct or complete your personal information;
•You have a right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information for specific purposes; and
•If you wish us to delete your personal information, you may request that we do so.Anyrequests received by Hayston Golf Club will be considered under applicable data protection legislation. If you remain dissatisfied, you have a right to raise a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office at www.ico.org.uk
HAYSTON GOLF CLUB
Campsie Road, Kirkintilloch, Glasgow G66 1RN
Tel. +44 (0)141 775 0723
email:
Not readable? Change text.
Send
Start typing and press Enter to search
